女贞路
我早该想到会在这里遇到你
I should've known that you would be here,
麦格教授
Professor McGonagall.
晚上好 邓不利多教授
Good evening, Professor Dumbledore.
传闻是真的吗 阿不思?
Are the rumors true, Albus?
我想是真的 教授
I'm afraid so, professor.
有好消息
The good
也有坏消息
and the bad.
那个孩子呢?
And the boy?
海格会把他带到这儿来
Hagrid is bringing him.
你觉得这么做明智吗?
Is it wise
把这种大事交给海格去办?
to trust Hagrid with something so important?
教授 我可以把命交到海格手中
Professor, I would trust Hagrid with my life.
邓不利多教授
Professor Dumbledore, sir.
麦格教授
Professor McGonagall.
没遇到什么麻烦吧 海格?
No problems, I trust, Hagrid?
没有 先生
No, sir.
我们飞过布里斯托尔的时候小家伙就睡着了
Little tyke fell asleep as we were flying over Bristol.
小心别吵醒他
Try not to wake him.
你看
There you go.
你觉得把他交给这些人好吗?
Do you really think it's safe, leaving him with these people?
我在这里观察了一整天
I've watched them all day.
真是一群无可救药的麻瓜
They're the worst sort of Muggles imaginable.
- 他们真的是...  - 他在世上唯一的亲人
- They really are...  - The only family he has.
这孩子将来会非常有名
He'll be famous.
我们世界中的每个孩子
Every child in our world
都会知道他的名字
will know his name.
完全正确
Exactly.
最好是让他成长时远离这一切
He's far better off growing up away from all of that.
等他能够接受的时候再告诉他
Until he's ready.
好了 好了 海格
There, there, Hagrid.
毕竟又不是永别
It's not really goodbye, after all.
德思礼夫妇敬启
萨里郡小惠金区女
贞路4号
祝你好运
Good luck...
哈利波特
...Harry Potter.
哈利波特与魔法石
起床! 快起床!
Up. Get up!
快点!
Now!
快醒来 表弟! 要去动物园啰!
Wake up, cousin! We're going to the zoo!
我们的小寿星来了
Here he comes, the birthday boy.
生日快乐 儿子
Happy birthday, son.
快去煮早餐 不准烧焦东西
Cook breakfast. And try not to burn anything.
是 佩妮姨妈
Yes, Aunt Petunia.
我希望今天一切顺心
I want everything to be perfect...
这可是我们达力的大日子
...for my Dudley's special day!
快呀!
Hurry up!
给我咖啡 小子
Bring my coffee, boy.
是 弗农姨父
Yes, Uncle Vernon.
是不是很棒呀 亲爱的?
Aren't they wonderful, darling?
一共有几个?
How many are there?
三十六个 我自己数的
36. Counted them myself.
三十六个? 但去年有三十七个
36?! But last year I had 37!
但有些礼物比去年的大一点呀
But some are bigger than last year's.
我管它有多大
I don't care how big they are.
好 好 我们这就要去买
Now now now This is what we're going to do.
那我们出去时
Is that when we go out
就再去帮你买两个新礼物
We're going to buy you two new presents.
怎么样 小乖乖?
How's that pumpkin?
要去动物园了
It should be a lovely day at the zoo.
一定可以玩得很开心 真期待
I'm really looking forward to it.
我警告你 小子
I'm warning you now, boy.
要是有任何怪事发生
Any funny business
只要一点点
any at all...
你就一个礼拜不准吃饭
...and you won't have any meals for a week.
上车
Get in.
爬虫类馆
叫它动嘛
Make it move.
动呀!
Move!
快动呀
它睡着了
He's asleep!
真没劲!
He's boring.
真对不起
Sorry about him.
他不了解你的感受 像这样
He doesn't understand what it's like,
一天又一天地躺在这儿
lying there day after day...
看人们硬把丑脸贴到你面前
...watching people press their ugly faces in on you.
你听得懂我的话?
Can you hear me?
只是...
It's just,
我以前从来没跟蛇讲过话
I've never talked to a snake before.
你...
Do you?
我是说 你常跟人说话吗?
I means. Do you talk to people often?
你是从缅甸来的 对吧?
You're from Burma, aren't you?
那儿是不是很美?
Was it nice there?
你想家吗?
Do you miss your family?
人工喂养样本
我懂了
I see.
我也一样
That's me as well.
我没见过我的父母
I never knew my parents either.
让开! 妈妈! 爸爸!
Moving. Mummy, Dad, come here
你绝对想不到这只蛇在干嘛
you won't believe what this snake is doing!
谢谢
Thanks.
愿意效劳
Anytime.
蛇!
Snake!
妈妈 妈咪
Mum! Mummy!
救救我 救命呀
Help me! Help me!
宝贝儿子 你是怎么进去的?
My darling boy! How did you get in there?
我的天哪 你是怎么进去的?
Who did this? How did you get in there?
那是一条蛇吗?
Is there a snake?
没事的 小甜心
It's all right, sweetheart.
我们会帮你把这湿冷的衣服脱掉
We'll get you out of these cold clothes.
这是怎么回事?
What happened?
我发誓我真的不知道
I swear, I don't know!
玻璃忽然消失
The glass was there and then it was gone,
就像魔法一样
like magic.
世上根本就没有魔法
There's no such thing as magic.
笑一笑
And smile!
弗农  看看你儿子  真不敢相信
Vernon, look at him! I can't believe it!
一周后他就去斯麦尔丁中学了
In a week, he'll be off to Smeltings.
斯麦尔丁人  真是我最骄傲的一刻
Caveat Smeltonia. Proudest moment of my life.
我不会也要穿那玩意吧
Will I have to wear that too?
什么  你
What?You?
也想去那上学
Go to Smeltings?
别傻了  你去公立学校
Don't be stupid! You're going to the state school.
等我染好了你就穿这件
This is what you'll wear when I finish dyeing it.
那是达力的旧校服  比我大了不知道多少圈
That's Dudley's old uniform. It'll fit like old elephant skin.
我看你穿正合适
Fit you well enough.
快去取邮件  赶紧
Go get the post. Go!
哈利·波特先生亲启
萨里郡小惠金区
女贞路4号楼梯下碗橱内
玛姬吃了个坏油螺生病了
Marge is ill. Ate a funny whelk.
-爸爸  看  哈利有封信  -那是我的
- Dad, look! Harry's got a letter! - It's mine!
你的  谁会给你写信啊
Yours? Who'd be writing to you?
我看你怎么收信
No more mail through this letterbox.
祝你工作愉快  老公
Have a lovely day at the office, dear.
去去  快滚
Shoo! Go on.
星期天真是好啊
Fine day, Sunday.
依我看  一周最好的就是今天  达力  为什么呢
In my opinion, best day of the week. Why is that, Dudley?
-因为星期天不送信吗  -被你说中了  哈利
- Because there's no post on Sundays? - Right you are, Harry!
星期天没人送信
No post on Sunday.
没有该死的信了  没了
No blasted letters today! No, sir.
一封该死的信也没有  没有
Not one single bloody letter. Not one!
没那些该死的  恶心的
No, sir, not one blasted, miserable...
快停下来
Make it stop, please!
停下来
Stop it!
妈妈  发生什么事了
Mummy, what's happening?
给我  把那封信给我
Give me that! Give me that letter!
放开我
Get off!
那是我的信  放开我
They're my letters! Let go of me!
我受够了  我们离开这
That's it! We're going away!
走的远远的  谁也找不到
Far away, where they can't find us!
爸爸是不是疯了
Daddy's gone mad, hasn't he?
哈利  生日快乐
许个愿吧  哈利
Make a wish, Harry.
谁在外面
Who's there?
真不好意思
Sorry about that.
我要求你马上离开  你这是私闯民宅
I demand that you leave at once. You are breaking and entering.
闭嘴吧  德斯礼  你这个老混蛋
Dry up, Dursley, you great prune.
上次见你时你还是个小不点  哈利
I haven't seen you since you was a baby, Harry.
你比我想象中长得结实嘛
You're a bit more along than I expected.
尤其是那小肚皮
Particularly in the middle.
我不是哈利
I'm not Harry.
-我才是  -当然是你啦
- I am. - Well, of course you are.
有东西给你
Got something for you.
我不小心坐了一下  但应该还是挺好吃的
Afraid I sat on it, but I imagine it'll taste fine just the same.
我自己烤的  还写了字
Baked it myself, words and all.
谢谢你
Thank you.
11岁生日可不是每天都有的  对吧
It's not every day your young man turns 11, is it?
不好意思  你是哪位
Excuse me, but who are you?
鲁伯·海格  霍格沃兹的场地和钥匙保管员
Rubeus Hagrid, Keeper of Keys and Grounds at Hogwarts.
-霍格沃兹你总知道吧  -对不起  我不知道
- Of course, you know about Hogwarts. - Sorry, no.
你从没想过你爸妈在哪儿学会的吗
Didn't you ever wonder where your mum and dad learned it all?
学会什么
Learned what?
你是个巫师  哈利
You're a wizard, Harry.
-我是什么  -巫师
- I'm a what? - A wizard.
还是个厉害巫师  只要你好好学习
A good one, I'd wager, once you're trained up.
我想你搞错了  我是说
No, you've made a mistake. I mean
我怎么会是巫师
I can't be a wizard.
我只是哈利  只是个小男孩
I mean, I'm just Harry. Just Harry.
好吧  哈利  你生气或害怕的时候
Well, Just Harry, did you ever make anything happen?
有没有做出过你自己也无法解释的事情
Anything you couldn't explain, when you were angry or scared?
亲爱的波特先生  很荣幸通知您
"Dear Mr. Potter, We are pleased to accept you
您已被霍格沃兹魔法学校录取
at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. "
他才不会去
He will not be going I tell you!
在收留他的那天  我们就发誓要阻止这一切
We swore when we took him that we'd put a stop to all this rubbish.
你们知道  怎么从来没告诉过我
You knew? You knew all along and you never told me?
我们当然知道  你也是那种货色
Of course we knew. How could you not be?
就像我那姐姐一个样子
My perfect sister being who she was.
我爸妈在她收到信那天多么自豪
My mother and father were so proud the day she got her letter.
我们家出了个女巫  真是太棒了
"We have a witch in the family. Isn't it wonderful?"
只有我才知道她的底细
I was the only one to see her for what she was.
她是个怪胎
A freak!
然后她认识了那个波特  又有了你
Then she met that Potter, and then she had you
我就知道你也是那种货色
and I knew you would be the same.
一样奇怪  也是怪胎
Just as strange, just as abnormal.
然后她就把自己炸死了  我们只能收留你
And then she went and got herself blown up, and we got landed with you.
炸死  你说我爸妈死于车祸
Blown up? You told me my parents died in a car crash.
什么车祸  车祸能杀了莉莉和詹姆斯吗
A car crash? A car crash killed Lily and James Potter?
-总得编个理由吧  -这是侮辱  这是诽谤
- We had to say something. - It's an outrage! A scandal!
他才不会去呢
He'll not be going.
你个大块头麻瓜想阻止吗
And I suppose a great Muggle like you is going to stop him, are you?
麻瓜
Muggle?
不会魔法的人
Non-magic folk.
这孩子刚出生就注定要去
This boy's had his name down since he were born.
他要去最好的魔法学校
He's going to the finest school of witchcraft and wizardry.
现在的校长
He'll be under the finest
是霍格沃兹有史以来最好的
headmaster Hogwarts has seen,
阿布思·邓布利多
Albus Dumbledore.
我才不会付钱让一个老糊涂去教他变戏法呢
I will not pay to have a crackpot old fool teach him magic tricks.
不许你侮辱邓布利多
Never insult Albus Dumbledore
在我面前
in front of me.
请不要告诉霍格沃兹的任何人
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell anyone at Hogwarts about that.
他们禁止我使用魔法
Strictly speaking I'm not supposed to do magic.
没问题
Okay.
我们要迟到了  得快走
We're a bit behind schedule. Best be off.
当然了  除非你想留在这
Unless you'd rather stay, of course.
第一年新生需要准备  三件长袍
First years will require three sets of work robes.
一根魔杖
one wand. "
基础装备  哈利
Essential bit of equipment, Harry.
一双龙皮手套
One pair of dragon hide gloves.
是真的龙皮做的吗
Hagrid, do they mean from a real dragon?
不是肯定企鹅的皮  是吧
They don't mean a penguin, do they?
哎  真想养一条龙啊
Crikey. I'd love a dragon.
你想养龙
You'd like a dragon?
龙被大家误解了  哈利
Vastly misunderstood beasts, Harry.
大家都误解了
Vastly misunderstood.
所有的学生都必须准备
All students must be equipped with
一个二号大坩埚
one standard size 2 pewter cauldron
还可以自带
and may bring, if they desire,
一只猫头鹰  猫或是蟾蜍
either an owl, a cat or a toad.
在伦敦能找到这些东西吗
Can we find all this in London?
只要你找对地方
If you know where to go.
你来啦  海格
Ah, Hagrid!
还是老样子吗
The usual, I presume?
谢了  汤姆  今天要替霍格沃兹办正事
No, thanks, Tom. I'm on official Hogwarts business.
在帮小哈利买学习用品呢
Just helping Harry buy his school supplies.
我的老天爷  是哈利·波特
Bless my soul. It's Harry Potter!
欢迎回来  波特先生  欢迎
Welcome back, Mr. Potter. Welcome back.
我是桃丽丝·克罗克福德  见到你太荣幸了
Doris Crockford. I can't believe I'm meeting you at last.
哈利·波特  我的荣幸之情无法言喻
Harry Potter. Can't tell you how pleased I am to meet you.
你好  教授  差点没看到您
Hello, professor. I didn't see you there
哈利  这是奇洛教授
Harry, this is Professor Quirrell.
他在霍格沃兹教黑魔法防御术
He will be teaching your Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts.
很高兴见到你
Oh, nice to meet you.
奇妙又可怕的学科
Fearfully fascinating subject.
不过你用不着学  是吧
Not that you need it, eh, Potter?
好吧  该走了  好多东西要买
Yes, well, must be going now. Lots to buy.
再见
Goodbye.
看  哈利  你很出名
See, Harry? You're famous.
但这是为什么 海格
- See, Harry? You're famous. - But why am I famous Hagrid?
大家为什么都知道我是谁
All those people back there, how is it they know who I am?
由我来告诉你可能不太合适  哈利
I'm not sure I'm the right person to tell you that.
哈利  欢迎来到对角巷
Welcome, Harry, to Diagon Alley.
这里可以买鹅毛笔和墨水
Here, you get your quills and ink.
那边  可以买到捣鼓魔法的各种小玩意
Over there, all your bits and bobs for doing wizardry.
这可是世界级的飞天扫把
It's a world-class racing broom.
快看  是最新的光轮2000
Look at it! The new Nimbus 2000!
这是最快的扫帚了
It's the fastest model yet.
光轮两千
可是我拿什么买呢 海格
But Hagrid, how am I to pay for all this?
我又没有钱
I haven't any money.
你的钱在那 哈利
There's your money. Harry
古灵阁  巫师银行
Gringotts, the wizard bank.
要存东西  那里最安全
Ain't no safer place, not one.
当然除了霍格沃兹
Except perhaps Hogwarts.
海格  那些是什么东西
Hagrid, what exactly are these things?
他们是妖精  哈利
They're goblins, Harry.
妖精很聪明  但却不怎么友善
Clever as they come, goblins, but not the most friendly of beasts.
最好跟紧我
Best stay close.
哈利·波特先生想取一些钱
Mr. Harry Potter wishes to make a withdrawal.
那么  哈利·波特先生带钥匙了吗
And does Mr. Harry Potter have his key?
等一下  我看看放哪了
Wait a minute. Got it here somewhere.
在这  这小玩意
Ha! There's the little devil.
还有件事
And there's something else as well.
邓布利多教授给了我这个
Professor Dumbledore gave me this.
最高机密
致对角巷  古灵阁银行  首席妖精
是在那个金库的那个东西
It's about You-Know-What in vault you-know-which.
那好吧
Very well.
687号金库
Vault 687.
请给我灯
Lamp, please.
钥匙
Key, please.
你不会以为你父母什么都不给你留吧
Did you think your parents would leave you with nothing, did you?
-713号金库  -里面是什么  海格
- Vault 713. - What's in there, Hagrid?
无可奉告 哈利
Can't tell you. Harry
霍格沃兹公务
Hogwarts business.
最高机密
Very secret.
退后
Stand back.
这事最好不要告诉任何人  哈利
Best not to mention this to anyone, Harry.
我还需要  一根魔杖
I still need a wand.
魔杖的话  去奥利凡德吧
A wand? You want Ollivanders.
最好的魔杖店
There ain't no place better.
你去那里买吧  然后等着
Why don't you run along there and wait.
我还有别的事  不会太久
I just got one more thing I got to do. It won't be long.
有人吗
Hello?
终于见到您了  波特先生
I wondered when I'd be seeing you, Mr. Potter.
当年你的父母
It seems only yesterday
就是在这买的第一根魔杖
...that your mother and father
仿佛是昨天的事
were in here buying their first wands.
试试这根
Here we are.
挥一下试试
Give it a wave.
看来这根不行
Apparently not.
也许
Perhaps...
这根能行
...this.
不  不  绝对不行  没关系
No, no, definitely not. No matter.
兴许是这根
I wonder...
奇妙
Curious.
真是太奇妙了
Very curious.
抱歉  什么地方让您觉得奇妙
Sorry, but what's curious?
我记得我卖出的每一根魔杖  波特先生
I remember every wand I've ever sold, Mr. Potter.
碰巧这根魔杖
It so happens that the phoenix...
和另一根魔杖的杖芯
...whose tail feather resides in your wand, gave another feather.
是同一只凤凰身上的羽毛
Just one other.
奇妙之处在于这根魔杖竟选择了你
It is curious that you should be destined for this wand...
因为它的兄弟给了你那道伤疤
...when its brother gave you that scar.
那根魔杖的主人是谁
And who owned that wand?
我们从不提起他的名字
We do not speak his name.
是魔杖选择巫师  波特先生
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
原因向来无法解释
It's not always clear why.
但我觉得
But I think it is clear...
你会成就一番大事业的
...that we can expect great things from you.
毕竟  连名字都不能提的那个人
After all, He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named...
也大有成就
...did great things.
尽管可怕
Terrible...
却还是大事
...yes, but great.
哈利
Harry!
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
你还好吗  哈利
You all right, Harry?
怎么不吭声
You seem very quiet.
他杀了我父母  对不对
He killed my parents, didn't he?
给我留下这道伤疤的人
The one who gave me this.
你知道的  海格  你一定知道
You know, Hagrid. I know you do.
首先你要知道一件很重要的事
First, and understand this because it's very important:
巫师并不一定都是好人
Not all wizards are good.
有些巫师会变坏  几年前
Some of them go bad. A few years ago...
有个巫师变得很坏很坏
...there was a wizard who went as bad as you can go.
他的名字叫伏...
And his name was V...
-他的名字叫伏... -你要不要写下来
- His name was V... - Maybe if you wrote it down?
不了  我不会写
No, I can't spell it.
好吧  他叫伏地魔
All right, Voldemort.
伏地魔
Voldemort?
那是段黑暗的日子  哈利  太黑暗了
It was dark times, Harry. Dark times.
当时伏地魔聚集了一批爪牙
Voldemort started to gather some followers.
拉拢他们投靠邪恶势力
Brought them over to the Dark Side.
反抗他的人都被杀害了
Anyone that stood up to him ended up dead.
你的父母奋起反抗
Your parents fought against him.
凡是他决意要杀的人  都活不下来
But nobody lived once he decided to kill them.
无人幸免
Nobody, not one.
除了你
Except you.
我吗  伏地魔想要杀我吗
Me? Voldemort tried to kill me?
没错  你额头的伤疤可不寻常  哈利
Yes. That ain't no ordinary cut on your forehead, Harry.
只有咒语才能
A mark like that only comes
留下这种伤疤  而且是很邪恶的咒语
from being touched by a curse, an evil curse at that.
那伏...那个神秘人后来怎么样了
What happened to V...? To You-Know-Who?
有些人说他死了
Well, some say he died.
简直是一派胡言
Codswallop, in my opinion.
我觉得他还活着
Nope, I reckon he's out there still...
只是没力气再回来了
...too tired to carry on.
但有一件事很肯定
But one thing's certain.
那天晚上你一定让他元气大伤
Something about you stumped him that night.
所以你才这么有名
That's why you're famous.
所以大家都认识你
That's why everybody knows your name.
你是大难不死的男孩
You're the boy who lived.
看什么看
What are you looking at?
啊呀  已经这个点了
Blimey, is that the time?
抱歉  哈利  我得先走了
Sorry, Harry, I'm gonna have to leave you.
邓布利多等着要他的...
Dumbledore will be wanting his...
他等着要见我
Well, he'll be wanting to see me.
你的火车还有10分钟就开了
Your train leaves in 10 minutes.
这是你的票  把票收好 哈利
Here's your ticket. Stick  to it. Harry,
这很重要 看好你的票
that's very important. Stick to your ticket,
九又四分之三站台
"Platform 9 3/4"?
但是海格  票上写错了吧
But, Hagrid, there must be a mistake.
这里写着九又四分之三站台
This says platform 9 3/4.
根本没有这种站台  对吧
There's no such thing, is there?
抱歉
Sorry.
不好意思
Excuse me.
往左走
On your left.
请问九又四分之三站台在哪里
Can you tell me where I might find platform 93/4?
九又四分之三  你在寻我开心吗
9 3/4? Think you're being funny, do you?
每年都一样
It's the same every year,
当然挤满了麻瓜 快点
packed with Muggles of course. Come on!
-麻瓜  -九又四分之三站台  这边
- Muggles? - Platform 9 3/4, this way.
好了  珀西  你先来
All right, Percy, you first.
弗雷德  你接着
Fred, you next.
他才不是弗雷德  我才是
He's not Fred, I am.
亏你还是妈妈  连你都分不清
Honestly, woman, you call yourself our mother?
抱歉  乔治
I'm sorry, George.
我开玩笑的  我是弗雷德
I'm only joking. I am Fred.
不好意思
Excuse me.
请问该怎么
Could you tell me how to...?
怎么去站台吗  别担心亲爱的
How to get onto the platform? Not to worry, dear.
罗恩也是第一次去霍格沃茨
It's Ron's first time to Hogwarts as well.
你只要穿过
All you do is walk straight
9站台和10站台之间的那道墙就行了
at the wall between platforms 9 and 10.
紧张的话就小跑过去
Best to run if you're nervous.
祝你好运
Good luck.
（九又四分之三站台）
（霍格沃茨特快车）
抱歉我能坐这里吗
Excuse me. Do you mind? Everywhere else is full.
别的车厢都坐满了
Everywhere else is full.
坐吧
Not at all.
我叫罗恩  罗恩·韦斯莱
I'm Ron, by the way. Ron Weasley.
我叫哈利  哈利·波特
I'm Harry. Harry Potter.
果然是真的
So... So it's true!
你真的有...
I mean, do you really have the...?
-有什么  -那个伤疤
- The what? - The scar?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
帅呆了
Wicked!
要不要买点东西吃啊  孩子们
Anything off the trolley, dears?
不  谢了  我自己带了
No, thanks. I'm all set.
我们全要了
We'll take the lot.
什么是比比多味豆
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans?
就是各种口味都有
They mean every flavor.
有巧克力味的和薄荷味的
There's chocolate and peppermint and also...
还有菠菜  肝脏  牛肚味
...spinach, liver and tripe.
乔治说他有次吃到过鼻屎味的
George sweared he got a booger-flavored one once.
这是真的青蛙吗
Are they real frogs?
这只是个咒语  主要是收集卡片用的
It's a spell. Besides, it's the cards you want.
每包附有一张著名巫师的卡片
Each pack's got a famous witch or wizard.
我已经收集了差不多500张了
I've got about 500 meself.
看好它
Watch it!
运气真背  它们只能跳那一下
That's rotten luck. They've only got one good jump in them.
-我这张是邓布利多  -我有六张了
- I've got Dumbledore! - I got about six of him.
他不见了
Hey, he's gone!
你总不能让他一直呆在卡片里面吧
You can't expect him to hang around all day, can you?
这个是斑斑  它真可怜  对吧
This is Scabbers. Pathetic, isn't he?
还好吧
A little.
弗雷德教了我一个咒语能把它变成黄色
Fred gave me a spell to turn him yellow.
-想见识下吗  -好啊
- Want to see? - Yeah.
你们有看见一只蟾蜍吗
Has anyone seen a toad?
-纳威把它给弄丢了  -没见过
- A boy named Neville's lost one. - No.
你这是要施魔法吗
Oh, are you doing magic?
让我们来瞧瞧吧
Let's see, then.
阳光  雏菊  甜奶油
Sunshine, daisies, butter mellow
把这只傻乎乎的肥老鼠变黄
Turn this stupid, fat rat yellow
你确定那个真的是咒语吗
Are you sure that's a real spell?
看来不怎么样  是吧
Well, it's not very good, is it?
我也试过几个简单的咒语
I've only tried a few simple ones myself...
但都很有用
...but they've all worked for me.
举个例子
For example:
修复一新
Oculus Reparo.
好多了  是不是
That's better, isn't it?
我的天  你是哈利·波特
Holy cricket, you're Harry Potter!
我叫赫敏·格兰杰  你呢
I'm Hermione Granger. And you are...?
-我叫罗恩·韦斯莱  -幸会
- I'm Ron Weasley. - Pleasure.
你们俩最好把袍子都穿上
You two better change into robes.
我们快到了
I expect we'll be arriving soon.
你鼻子上有块东西  你知道吗
You've got dirt on your nose by the way. Did you know?
在这儿
Just there.
好了  新生  这边走
Right, then. First years, this way, please!
来吧  新生  别害羞  快点快点
Come on, first years, don't be shy. Come on now, hurry up.
你好  哈利
Oh, Harry.
你好  海格
Hi, Hagrid.
来  走这边上船
Right, then. This way to the boats.
快点  跟着我
Come on now, follow me.
帅呆了
Wicked.
欢迎来到霍格沃茨
Welcome to Hogwarts.
再过一会你们就会
Now, in a few moments you'll pass
走过这扇门和其他同学共聚一堂
through these doors and join your classmates.
但在你们到餐厅入席之前
But before you take your seats,
需要先为你们分派学院
you must be sorted into your houses.
分别有格兰芬多  赫奇帕奇
They are Gryffindor, Hufflepuff...
拉文克劳以及斯莱特林四个学院
...Ravenclaw and Slytherin.
在校期间  学院就是你们的家
While you're here, your house will be like your family.
你们的出色表现会为学院赢得加分
Your triumphs will earn you points.
而任何违规行为则会给学院减分
Any rule-breaking and you will lose points.
在年终时
At the end of the year,
获最高分的学院可获得学院杯
the house with the most points wins the house cup.
莱福
Trevor!
对不起
Sorry.
分院仪式马上就要开始了
The Sorting Ceremony will begin momentarily.
火车上的传闻果然是真的
It's true then, what they're saying on the train.
哈利·波特来霍格沃茨了
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts.
哈利·波特
Harry Potter?
这是克拉布和高尔
This is Crabbe and Goyle.
我是马尔福
And I'm Malfoy.
德拉科·马尔福
Draco Malfoy.
觉得我的名字很好笑是吗
Think my name's funny, do you?
一眼就知道你是谁
I've no need to ask yours.
红头发和旧长袍
Red hair and a hand-me-down robe?
想必是韦斯莱家的人
You must be a Weasley.
你很快会发现有些巫师家族
You'll find out some wizarding families
就是要高级些 波特
are better than others, Potter.
你不会想和这种货色交朋友的
You don't want to go making friends with the wrong sort.
我倒是可以做你朋友
I can help you there.
我还分得清好坏  谢了
I think I can tell the wrong sort for myself, thanks.
一切准备就绪了  跟我走
We're ready for you now. Follow me.
这个屋顶不是真的
The ceiling isn't real.
它被施了魔咒看上去像夜空一样
It's bewitched to look like the night sky.
我在《霍格沃茨校史》里读到过
I read about it in Hogwarts, A History.
请你们先在这里等着
Will you wait along here, please?
现在  在我们开始前
Now, before we begin...
邓布利多校长有几句话要说
...Professor Dumbledore would like to say a few words.
我要先宣布几条新学期必须注意的事项
I have a few start-of-term notices I wish to announce.
一年级新生们请注意
The first years, please note...
禁林严禁学生进入
...that the Dark Forest is strictly forbidden to all students.
另外  我们的管理员
Also, our caretaker, Mr. Filch,
费尔奇先生要我提醒各位
has asked me to remind you...
如果不想死的很惨的话
...that the third-floor corridor is out of bounds...
就不要进入三楼右手边的走廊
...to everyone who does not wish to die a most painful death.
谢谢
Thank you.
当我叫到你的名字时
When I call your name,
请上前来
you will come forth.
我会给你戴上分院帽
I shall place the Sorting Hat on your head...
为你分派学院
...and you will be sorted into your houses.
赫敏·格兰杰
Hermione Granger.
哦 不
Oh, no.
好了  放松
Okay, relax.
我告诉你  那人脑子绝对不正常
Mental, that one, I'm telling you.
好  好
Right, then. Right.
好了  格兰芬多
Okay. Gryffindor!
德拉科·马尔福
Draco Malfoy.
斯莱特林
Slytherin!
那些变坏的巫师都是斯莱特林出身的
Every wizard who went bad was in Slytherin.
苏珊·博恩斯
Susan Bones.
哈利  怎么了
Harry, what is it?
没事
Nothing.
我没事
I'm fine.
让我想想
Let's see...
知道了  赫奇帕奇
I know! Hufflepuff!
罗恩·韦斯莱
Ronald Weasley.
又一个韦斯莱  我知道该把你分到哪了
Another Weasley! I know just what to do with you.
格兰芬多
Gryffindor!
哈利·波特
Harry Potter.
难  着实难
Difficult, very difficult.
看得出很有勇气  心地也不坏
Plenty of courage, I see. Not a bad mind, either.
而且很有天赋
There's talent, oh, yes.
急切的想要证明自己
And a thirst to prove yourself.
该把你分去哪个学院呢
But where to put you?
不去斯莱特林
Not Slytherin
不去斯莱特林  你确定吗
Not Slytherin, eh? Are you sure?
你能成大器
You could be great, you know.
你的小脑瓜里都写着呢
It's all here, in your head.
斯莱特林能帮你
And Slytherin will help you
走向辉煌  这是毫无疑问的
on the way to greatness, no doubt about that.
不要嘛  既然你决心已定
No? Well, if you're sure.
那就去
Better be...
格兰芬多吧
...Gryffindor!
波特来这了
We got Potter!
请注意
Your attention, please.
宴会开始
Let the feast begin.
我是混血
I'm half and half.
我爸是麻瓜  我妈是女巫
Me dad's a Muggle. Mum's a witch.
我爸知道的时候吓了一大跳
Bit of a nasty shock for him when he found out.
珀西  在和奇洛教授交谈的那个老师是谁
Percy, who's that teacher talking to Professor Quirrell?
那是斯内普教授  斯莱特林的院长
Professor Snape, head of Slytherin house.
-他教什么科目  -魔药学
- What's he teach? - Potions.
但他最感兴趣的是黑魔法防御术
But he fancies the Dark Arts Defences.
他觊觎奇洛教授的位子很多年了
He's been after Quirrell's job for years.
大家好  你好啊
Hello! How are you?
欢迎来到格兰芬多
Welcome to Gryffindor.
那是血人巴罗
It's the Bloody Baron!
你好  尼可拉斯爵士
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
暑期过得愉快吗
Have a nice summer?
不开心  我想参加
Dismal. Once again, my request
无头骑士狩猎  但又一次被拒绝了
to join the Headless Hunt has been denied.
我知道  你是"差点没头的尼克"
I know you. You're Nearly Headless Nick.
我更喜欢别人叫我尼古拉斯爵士
I prefer Sir Nicholas, if you don't mind.
差点没头
"Nearly" Headless?
你怎么能差点没头呢
How can you be nearly headless?
就像这样
Like this.
格兰芬多的同学请跟我来
Gryffindors, follow me, please.
大家跟上  谢谢
Keep up. Thank you.
拉文克劳的同学跟我来  这边走
Ravenclaw, follow me. This way.
这是通往宿舍最直的路径
This is the most direct path to the dormitories.
留神那些楼梯  它们随时会变
Keep an eye on the staircases. They like to change.
请大家跟紧了  跟我走
Keep up, please, and follow me.
走快点  快点  快点
Quickly now, come on. Come on.
那幅画在动
That picture's moving.
-看那一幅  -我想她喜欢你
- Look at that one. - I think she fancies you.
-快看啊  -那个女孩是谁
- Look! - Who's that girl?
欢迎来到霍格沃茨
Welcome to Hogwarts.
口令
Password?
龙渣
Caput Draconis.
大家跟我来  都跟上  快点
Follow me, everyone. Keep up. Quickly, come on.
在这里集合
Gather around here.
欢迎来到格兰芬多的公共休息室
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room.
男生宿舍在楼上左手边
Boys' dormitory is upstairs to the left.
女生的在楼上右手边
Girls, the same on your right.
你们的行李已经被送到楼上了
Your belongings have already been brought up.
赶上了
Made it!
你能想象老麦格知道我们迟到了
Can you imagine the look
脸色会多难看吗
on old McGonagall's face if we were late?
真是太厉害了
That was bloody brilliant!
多谢夸奖  韦斯莱先生
Thank you for that assessment.
或许把波特先生和你变成怀表
Perhaps it'd be more usefully
效果会更好些
if I transfigured Mr. Potter and yourself into a watch.
没准你们就知道准时的意义了
Then one of you might be on time.
我们迷路了
We got lost.
那我该把你们变成地图喽
Then perhaps a map?
我相信找到你们自己的座位不需要地图吧
I trust you don't need one to find your seats.
在我的课上
There will be no foolish
不准乱挥魔杖  不准乱念咒语
wand-waving or silly incantations in this class.
就个人而言  我不指望你们中大多数人
As such, I don't expect many of you to appreciate...
能够领会魔药学中的技术与奥妙
...the subtle science and exact art that is potion-making.
不过  对那极少数
However, for those select few...
拥有资质的人
...who possess the predisposition...
我可以教你们如何迷惑人的心智
...I can teach you how to bewitch the mind...
囚禁人的感官
...and ensnare the senses.
我可以教你们如何罐藏名声
I can tell you how to bottle fame
酿造荣誉
brew glory
甚至长生不死
and even put a stopper in death.
我还要重申
Then again,
也许有人觉得在霍格沃茨
maybe some of you have come to Hogwarts
蛊惑人心
迷惑感官
提高声望
创造辉煌
长生不老
仗着自己名气大
in possession with abilities so formidable
（这正是教授刚才讲的 这里哈利在做笔记）
就自信满满
that you feel confident enough...
觉得可以不专心听讲
...to not pay attention.
波特先生
Mr. Potter.
新生代的名人
Our new celebrity.
如果将水仙根粉末
What would I get if I added
加入艾草浸液中会得到什么
root of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?
你不知道  那我们换个问题
You don't know? Let's try again.
如果要找牛黄你应该从哪里着手
Where would you look if I asked you to find a bezoar?
我不知道  先生
I don't know, sir.
舟形乌头和狼毒乌头有什么区别
What is the difference between monkshood and wolfsbane?
我不知道  先生
I don't know, sir.
真遗憾
Pity.
显然  名声不代表一切
Clearly, fame isn't everything...
对吗  波特先生
...is it, Mr. Potter?
显然  赫敏知道答案
Clearly, Hermione knows.
不让她回答才真是遗憾
Seems a pity not to ask her.
安静
Silence.
把手放下  你这个傻丫头
Put your hand down, you silly girl!
仅供参考  波特
For your information, Potter...
水仙草根加艾草能制成强力的催眠药
...asphodel and wormwood make the sleeping potion so powerful
[第六部小说中该药剂再次出现]
也就是生死水
it is known the draught of the Living Dead.
牛黄是一种从公羊胃内取出的石头
A bezoar is a stone taken from the stomach of a goat's
可以化解绝大多数的毒药
and will save you from most of the poisons.
舟形乌头和狼毒乌头是同一种植物
Monkshood and wolfsbane they are the same plant,
也被统称为乌头
which also goes by the name of aconite.
那
Well...
你们为什么不把这些记下来
...why aren't you all copying this down?
格兰芬多的学生们注意了
And Gryffindors...
由于你们的同学对老师无礼
...note that five points will be taken from your house...
学院将被扣除5分
...for your classmate's cheek.
兔眼晶晶  竖琴幽幽
Eye of rabbit, harp string hum.
把这清水变美酒
Turn this water into rum
兔眼晶晶  竖琴幽幽
Eye of rabbit, harp string hum.
西莫想对那杯水做什么
What's Seamus going to do to that glass of water?
把它变成酒  昨天确实成功变出了淡茶
Turn it to rum. Actually managed a weak tea yesterday,
不过后来就...
before...
来邮件了
Mail's here.
我能借来看看吗  谢谢
Can I borrow this? Thanks.
看啊  纳威收到个记忆球
Look, Neville's got a Remembrall.
我在书里读到过
I've read about those. The
如果你忘记了事情  烟会变成红色
smoke turns red when you've forgotten something.
问题是  我不记得忘记了什么事情
The problem is, I can't remember what I've forgotten.
有人非法闯入了古灵阁  听这里
Hey Ron. Somebody broke into Gringotts. Listen.
相信是不明身份的黑巫师所为
"Believed to be the work of Dark wizards or witches unknown...
古灵阁的妖精承认有人闯入
...Gringotts goblins acknowledge
但是强调什么都没有失窃
the breach but insist nothing was taken.
遭窃的713号金库
The vault in question, number 713,
在当天早些时候已空无一物
had been emptied earlier that same day. "
奇怪  我和海格去的就是这个金库
That's odd. That's the vault Hagrid and I went to.
下午好  同学们
Good afternoon, class.
下午好  霍琦夫人
Good afternoon, Madam Hooch.
下午好  阿曼达
Good afternoon, Amanda.
下午好
Good afternoon.
欢迎参加你们的第一堂飞行课
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
你们还在等什么
What are you waiting for?
站到飞天扫帚左边去
Everyone Step up to the left side of the broomstick.
来啊  动作快点
Come on now, hurry up.
把右手放在扫帚的正上方说  起
Stick your right hand over the broom and say, "Up. "
起
Up!
Up.
起
起  起
Up. Up!
带点感情
With feeling.
起
Up.
闭嘴  哈利
Shut up, Harry.
拿到扫帚的同学
Now, once you've got hold of your broom,
我要你们骑上去
I want you to mount it.
抓紧了  小心别滑下来
Grip it tight. You don't wanna be sliding off than.
当我吹响哨子
When I blow my whistle,
我要你们每一个人都用力蹬地
I want each of you to kick off from the ground, hard.
让你们的扫帚飞起来
Keep your broom steady,
在空中停一会儿
hover for a moment...
然后微微前倾  回到地面
...then lean forward slightly and touch back down.
注意我的哨音  3  2
On my whistle. Three, two...
隆巴顿先生
Mr. Longbottom.
-隆巴顿先生  -下去  下去
- Mr. Longbottom! - Down, down!
纳威
Neville!
给我下来
Come back down this instant!
大家让开
Everyone out of the way!
他没事吧
Is he all right?
天哪  手腕骨折了
Oh, dear, it's a broken wrist.
可怜的孩子  来吧  站起来
Poor boy. Come on now, up you get.
在我送他去医疗室期间
Everyone has to Keep his feet firmly on the
你们都老老实实地呆在地上
ground while I take Mr. Longbottom to the hospital wing.
听明白了吗  不要让我看到天上有扫帚
Understand? I see a single broom in the air...
否则直接开除
...the one riding it will find himself
连魁地奇的边都碰不到
be expelled from Hogwarts before they can say Quidditch.
你们看到他的脸了吗
Did you see his face?
如果他抓着这个
If he had squeezed this,
就会记得用屁股着陆
he'd have remembered to fall on his arse.
把它给我  马尔福
Give it here, Malfoy.
不  我要藏起来让隆巴顿去找
No. I think I'll leave it somewhere for Longbottom to find.
藏在屋顶上怎么样
How about on the roof?
怎么了波特  够不着吗
What's the matter, Potter? Bit beyond your reach?
哈利别去  想想霍琦夫人说的话
Harry, no way! You heard what Madam Hooch said.
而且你还不知道怎么飞
Besides, you don't know how to fly.
大傻瓜
What an idiot.
把它给我  不然我把你打下去
Give it here or I'll knock you off your broom!
你就这点本事吗
Is that so?
要的话就自己去拿吧
Have it your way, then.
接得好  哈利
Nice going, Harry.
太棒了  哈利
That was wicked, Harry!
哈利·波特
Harry Potter!
跟我来
Follow me.
在这儿等着
You wait here.
对不起  奇洛教授
Professor Quirrell, excuse me.
能让伍德出来一下吗
Could I borrow Wood for a moment?
当然可以
Yes, of course.
波特  这位是奥利佛·伍德
Potter, this is Oliver Wood.
伍德  我给你找到个找球手
Wood, I have found you a Seeker.
你听说了吗
Have you heard?
哈利·波特成了格兰芬多新的找球手
Harry Potter's the new Gryffindor Seeker.
我就知道他准行
I always knew he'd do well.
找球手  但是新生从来没入选过院队
Seeker? But first years never make the house teams.
你一定是最年轻的魁地奇选手
You must be the youngest Quidditch player in...
百年来最年轻的  麦格说的
A century, McGonagall says.
好样的哈利  伍德都告诉我们了
Well done, Harry. Wood's just told us.
弗雷德和乔治也在队上
Fred and George are on the team,too.
击球手
Beaters.
我们的任务就是保护你
Our job is to make sure you
不要被揍得太惨
don't get bloodied up too bad.
打不了包票  魁地奇很野蛮
Can't make any promises. Rough game, Quidditch.
但是从来没有死过人  偶尔有人会消失
But no one's died in years. Someone vanishes occasionally.
不过一两个月后就会出现
But they'll turn up in a month or two.
去吧哈利  魁地奇很带劲
Go on,Harry. Quidditch is great.
最好玩的运动  你也会成为最棒的
Best game there is, and you'll be great too.
我从来没打过  要是出洋相了怎么办
I've never played. What if I make a fool of myself?
你才不会出洋相呢  有家族遗传
You won't make a fool of yourself. It's in your blood.
找球手  詹姆·波特  1971年
你从没说过你爸爸也是个找球手
You never told me your father was a Seeker too.
我不知道
I didn't know.
实话实说  这事挺玄乎的
I'm telling you, it's spooky.
关于你的事  赫敏知道的都比你多
She knows more about you than you do.
谁都比我多
Who doesn't?
出什么事了
What's happening?
楼梯自己会变  记得吗
The staircases change, remember?
-这边走  -不然楼梯一会儿又要动了
- Let's go this way. - Before the staircase moves again.
有没有人觉得我们走错地方了
Does anybody feel like we shouldn't be here?
我们不该进来的
We're not supposed to be here.
三楼是禁地
This is the third floor. It's forbidden.
我们离开这儿
Let's go.
-是费尔奇的猫  -快跑
- It's Filch's cat! - Run!
快点  躲到那扇门后面去
Quick, let's hide through that door!
-门锁上了  -我们完蛋了
- It's locked! - We're done for!
闪开
Move over!
阿拉霍洞开
Alohomora.
进来
Get in.
阿拉霍洞开?
Alohomora?
标准咒语手册  第七章
Standard Book of Spells, chapter seven.
有人进来了吗  亲爱的
Anyone here, my sweet?
走吧
Come on.
-费尔奇走了  -他以为这门锁着
- Filch is gone. - He thinks this door's locked.
-门是锁着的  -肯定要锁着
- It was locked. - And for good reason.
他们到底想干嘛
What are they doing,
把这样的东西关在学校里
keeping a thing like that locked up in a school?
你眼睛是用来干嘛的
You didn't use your eyes, aren't you?
没看到它站在哪儿吗
Didn't you see what it was standing on?
我没看它的脚  我光顾着看它的头了
I wasn't looking at its feet! I was preoccupied with its heads.
也许你没有注意到  它有三个头
Or maybe you didn't notice. There were three!
它站在一个暗门上  这肯定不是巧合
It was standing on a trap door. It wasn't there by accident.
它在看守着什么东西
It's guarding something.
看守东西
Guarding something?
没错  现在  如果你们俩不介意
That's right. Now, if you two don't mind,
我去睡了  免得你们两个想出什么妙计
I'm going to bed before either of you come up with another idea
害我们送命
to get us killed.
没准更糟  被开除
Or worse, expelled.
她哪个更糟都分不清吗
She needs to sort out her priorities.
魁地奇很简单  每支队伍有7个队员
Quidditch is easy to understand. Each team has seven players.
三个追球手  两个击球手
Three Chasers, two Beaters,
一个守门员和一个找球手  就是你
one Keeper and a Seeker. That's you.
一共有3种球  这种叫鬼飞球
There are three kinds of balls. This one's called the Quaffle.
追球手手持鬼飞球
The Chasers handle the Quaffle
把它扔进其中一个铁环
and try to put it through one of those hoops.
而我作为守门员要守住铁环  明白了吗
The Keeper, that's me, defends the hoops. With me so far?
明白了  那这些是什么
I think so. What are those?
你拿好这个
You better take this.
小心点  它回来了
Careful now, it's coming back.
干得不错  波特
Not bad, Potter.
你做击球手也不赖
You'd make a fair Beater.
那到底是什么
What was that?
游走球  淘气的小家伙
Bludger. Nasty little buggers.
不过你是个找球手
But you are a Seeker.
你唯一要关心的是这个球
The only thing I want you to worry about is this.
金色飞贼
The Golden Snitch.
-我喜欢这颗球  -你没尝过它的厉害
- I like this ball. - You like it now.
等着瞧  它飞得超快  快得都没影了
Just wait. It's wicked fast and damn near impossible to see.
我该怎么做
What do I do with it?
赶在对方的找球手之前抓住它
You catch it. Before the other team's Seeker.
抓到它  比赛就结束了
You catch this, the game's over.
抓到它  波特  我们就赢了
You catch this, Potter, and we win.
悬停魔咒
One of a wizard's most rudimentary skills
是基础咒语之一
is levitation...
就是让物体飞起来
...or the ability to make objects fly.
你们都拿到羽毛了吗  很好
Do you have your feathers? Good.
现在  不要忘记我们刚才练习过的
Now, don't forget the nice wrist movement
正确的魔杖挥舞手势
we've been practicing.
一挥一抖  大家一起来
The swish and flick. Everyone.
一挥  再一抖
The swish and flick.
做得很好  再念动咒语
Good. Oh, and enunciate.
羽加迪姆  勒维奥萨
Wingardium Leviosa.
你们来试试
Off you go, then.
羽加迪姆  勒维奥萨
Wingardium Leviosa.
不  停  停  停
No, stop, stop, stop!
你都要戳到别人的眼睛了
You're going to take someone's eye out.
而且你的咒语也念错了
Besides, you're saying it wrong.
是勒维"奥"萨  而不是勒维奥"萨"
It's Leviosa, not Leviosar.
你那么聪明  你倒是试试看啊  来啊
You do it then, if you're so clever. Go on, go on.
羽加迪姆  勒维奥萨
Wingardium Leviosa.
做得很好  大家看啊
Well done!  See here everyone,
格兰杰小姐做到了
Miss Granger's done it!
好极了
Splendid!
做得好  亲爱的
Well done, dear.
教授  我想我们这儿还需要一根羽毛
I think we're going to need another feather over here, professor.
是勒维"奥"萨  不是勒维奥"萨"
"It's Leviosa, not Leviosar. "
实话实说  她就是个噩梦
She's a nightmare, honestly!
难怪她交不到朋友
No wonder she hasn't got any friends.
我想她听见了
I think she heard you.
赫敏去哪儿了
Where's Hermione?
帕瓦蒂说她一直待在浴室里不出来
Parvati said she wouldn't come out of the bathroom.
她在里面哭了一下午
She said that she'd been in there all afternoon, crying.
巨怪  在地下室
Troll in the dungeon!
地下室有巨怪
应该告诉你们一下
Thought you ought to know.
安静
Silence!
请大家不要惊慌
Everyone will please not panic!
现在
Now
级长带领各自学院的同学回到宿舍
prefects will lead their house back to the dormitories.
老师们跟我去地下室
Teachers will follow me to the dungeons.
格兰芬多的同学  请跟上
Gryffindors, keep up, please,
保持警惕
and stay alert.
巨怪怎么会在学校出现
How could a troll get in?
肯定是被放进来的  巨怪都是大笨蛋
Not on its own. Trolls are really stupid.
也许是有人在恶作剧吧
Probably people playing jokes.
-干嘛  -赫敏还不知情呢
- What? - Hermione! She doesn't know.
看来巨怪不在地下室
I think the troll's left the dungeon.
它要进女生盥洗室
It's going into the girls' bathroom.
赫敏  快跑
Hermione, move!
救命  救命
Help! Help!
这边  大笨蛋
Hey, pea brain!
救命
Help!
别愣着不动啊
Do something!
-你让我干嘛  -随便
- What? - Anything!
-快点  -一挥一抖
- Hurry up! - Swish and flick.
羽加迪姆  勒维奥萨
Wingardium Leviosa.
太帅了
Cool.
它死了吗
Is it dead?
我看不像  是晕过去了
I don't think so. Just knocked out.
好恶心的鼻涕
Troll boogers.
天哪  都给我解释清楚这是怎么回事
Oh, my goodness! Explain yourselves, both of you!
事情是这样的...
Well, what it is...
都是我的错  麦格教授
It's my fault, Professor McGonagall.
格兰杰小姐
Miss Granger?
我找巨怪来了
I went looking for the troll.
以为自己搞得定它
I thought I could handle it.
结果我错了
But I was wrong.
要不是哈利和罗恩及时出现
If Harry and Ron hadn't come and found me,
我可能已经死了
I'd probably be dead.
即使是这样  这也是件傻事
Be that as it may, it was an extremely foolish thing to do.
想不到你这么冒失
I would have expected more rational behavior
太让我失望了 格兰杰小姐
on your part and am very disappointed in you. Miss. Granger
格兰芬多扣掉5分
Five points will be taken from Gryffindor
因为你严重的判断失误
for your serious lack of judgment.
至于你们两位先生
As for you two gentlemen.
要记住你们这次纯属走运
I just hope you realize how fortunate you are.
不是每个新生都能面对巨怪
Not many first-year students could take on a fully grown mountain troll
全身而退的
and live to tell the tale.
每个人
Five points
各奖励5分
will be awarded to each of you
算是为你们的狗屎运
for sheer dumb luck.
你们该走了  巨怪马上就要醒了
Perhaps you ought to go. It might wake up.
咒语用得好  让我们脱困了
Good of you to get us out of trouble.
我们救了她的性命呢
We did save her life.
要不是你惹恼了她  就没这一出了
She might not have needed saving if you hadn't insulted her.
朋友不就是这样吗
What are friends for?
再吃点面包吧  哥们
Take a bit of toast, mate. Go on.
罗恩说得没错 哈利
Ron's right. Harry.
今天你需要消耗体力
You'll need your strength today.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
祝你今天好运  波特
Good luck today, Potter.
话说回来 巨怪你都打败了
Then  again, now that You've proven yourself against a troll.
魁地奇比赛更是不在话下
A game of Quidditch should be easy work.
哪怕对手是斯莱特林
Even if it is against Slytherin.
-血迹是这么回事  -血迹
- That explains the blood. - Blood?
我觉得昨晚斯内普用巨怪声东击西
Last night, I'm guessing Snape let the troll in as a diversion
乘机闯过守护犬
so he could get past that three headed dog.
但被咬了  所以跛了
But he got bit, that's why he's limping.
他干嘛要招惹三头犬
But why would anyone go near that dog?
我在古灵阁的那天
The day I was at Gringotts,
海格在地下金库取出一样东西
Hagrid took something out of the vault.
他说这是霍格沃茨的公事
Said it was Hogwarts business,
高度机密
very secret.
你的意思是
So  you're saying...
那就是三头犬守护的东西
That's what the dog's guarding.
斯内普想偷走
That's what Snape wants.
这么早就送邮件吗
Bit early for mail, isn't it?
都没人给我寄过包裹呢
But I never get mail.
打开瞧瞧
Let's open it.
飞天扫帚
It's a broomstick.
这不是普通的飞天扫帚  哈利
That's not just a broomstick, Harry,
这可是光轮2000
It's a Nimbus 2000!
但这是谁...
But who...?
怕不怕  哈利
Scared, Harry?
一点点
A little.
这很正常
It's all right.
我第一次上场也是这样的
I felt the same way before my first game.
后来呢
What happened?
记不清了
I don't really remember.
两分钟  我被游走球击中脑袋
I took a Bludger to the head two minutes in.
在医院昏迷了一个星期
Woke up in hospital a week later.
大家好  欢迎观看霍格沃茨
Hello. Welcome to Hogwarts'
本学期首场魁地奇比赛
first Quidditch game of the season.
今天的比赛  由斯莱特林对战格兰芬多
Today's game, Slytherin versus Gryffindor!
球员们各就各位
The players take their positions
霍奇夫人步入球场  宣布比赛开始
as Madam Hooch steps onto the field to begin the game!
我希望今天的比赛
Now, I want a nice, clean game
公正  又精彩
from all of you!
游走球升空了
The Bludgers are up,
紧跟着的是金色飞贼
followed by the Golden Snitch.
记住  金色飞贼值150分
Remember, the Snitch is worth 150 points.
找球手逮住它  比赛就结束
The Seeker who catches the Snitch ends the game.
鬼飞球上天  比赛开始
The Quaffle is released and the game begins!
安吉丽娜·约翰逊进球
Angelina Johnson scores!
格兰芬多得10分
Ten points for Gryffindor!
漂亮
Well done!
斯莱特林得球
Slytherin takes the Quaffle.
布莱奇传球给马库斯·弗林特队长
Bletchley passes to Captain Marcus Flint.
格兰芬多再得10分
Another 10 points to Gryffindor!
给我
Give me that!
抢占那边
Take that side!
哈利的扫帚怎么回事
What's going on with Harry's broomstick?
斯内普在给扫帚下霉咒
It's Snape. He's jinxing the broom!
-真的吗  那怎么办  -看我的
- Jinxing the broom? What do we do? - Leave it to me.
快点  赫敏
Come on, Hermione!
火焰熊熊
Lacarnum Inflamarae.
火  你身上着火了
Fire! You're on fire!
冲
Go
他好像要吐了
Looks like he's gonna be sick.
他逮住金色飞贼了
He's got the Snitch!
哈利波特为队伍赢得了150分
Harry Potter receives 150 points for catching the Snitch!
格兰芬多胜出
Gryffindor wins!
别乱说
Nonsense!
斯内普干嘛要给哈利的扫帚下咒
Why would Snape put a curse on Harry's broom?
谁知道  他为什么要惹三头犬
Who knows? Why was he trying to get past that three-headed dog?
-谁告诉你们路威的  -路威
- Who told you about Fluffy? - Fluffy?
这个名字也有“毛球”的意思
那东西还有名字吗
That thing has a name?
当然了  那可是我的宠物
Of course he has a name. He's mine.
去年在酒吧我从爱尔兰人手里买下的
I bought him off an Irish feller I met down at the pub last year.
-用来给邓布利多看守...  -什么
- I lent him to Dumbledore to guard... - Yes?
我不该说的  够了  不许再问了
Shouldn't have said that. No more questions! Don't ask any more question!
这是最高机密
That's top-secret.
不管路威在看守什么
But whatever Fluffy's guarding,
那就是斯内普要偷的东西
Snape's trying to steal it.
胡说八道  斯内普教授可是霍格沃茨的老师
Codswallop. Professor Snape is a Hogwarts teacher.
谁知道  反正我看到他在下咒语
Hogwarts teacher or not, I know a spell when I see one.
我在书里读到过
I've read all about them.
需要眼睛紧盯目标  斯内普就没眨过眼
You've got to keep eye contact, and Snape wasn't blinking.
没错
Exactly.
你们三个听我说
Now, you listen to me, all three of you.
这件事太危险
You're meddling in things
你们不该搀和
that ought not to be meddled in. It's dangerous.
狗狗看护的东西
What that dog is guarding
只和邓布利多及尼古拉斯·勒梅有关
is stroctly between Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel.
尼古拉斯·勒梅
Nicholas Flamel?
糟糕  我说漏嘴了
I shouldn't have said that.
我又说漏嘴了
I should not have said that.
谁是尼古拉斯·勒梅
Nicholas Flamel. Who's Nicholas Flamel?
我不知道
I don't know.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
霍格沃茨的钟声响起
Ring the Hogwarts bell
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
轻施一个圣诞魔法
Cast a Christmas spell
骑士  走E5
Knight to e5.
王后  走E5
Queen to e5.
太暴力了
That's totally barbaric!
巫师象棋就是这样
That's wizard's chess.
你已经打包好行李了
I see you've packed.
你可没有
I see you haven't.
计划有变  我爸妈
Change of plans. My parents decided to
去罗马尼亚看望我哥查理去了
go to Romania to visit my brother Charlie.
他在那里研究火龙
He's studying dragons there.
也好  你可以协助哈利
Good. You can help Harry.
他正在图书馆寻找尼古拉斯·勒梅的信息呢
He's going to the library to look up Nicholas Flamel.
我们都翻遍了  还是一无所获
We've looked a hundred times!
别忘了还有禁书区
Not in the restricted section.
圣诞快乐
Happy Christmas.
我觉得咱们会被她带坏的
I think we've had a bad influence on her.
哈利  醒醒  快来看  哈利
Harry, wake up! Come on, Harry, wake up!
圣诞快乐  哈利
Happy Christmas, Harry.
圣诞快乐  罗恩
Happy Christmas, Ron.
你穿的是什么
What are you wearing?
妈妈织的毛衣  好像你也有一件
Oh, my mum made it. Looks like you've got one too.
-我的礼物  -是啊
- I've got presents? - Yeah.
就是这个
There they are.
"令尊过世前  把此物托付给我
"Your father left this in my possession before he died.
今物归原主  请妥善使用"
It is time it was returned to you. Use it well. "
这是什么东西
What is it?
像是斗篷
Some kind of cloak.
不错  穿上瞧瞧
Well, let's see, then. Put it on.
我的身体不见了
My body's gone!
我知道了  这是件隐形斗篷
I know what that is. That's an invisibility cloak!
我隐形了
I'm invisible?
这可是稀有宝贝
They're really rare.
奇怪  谁寄给你的
I wonder who gave it to you.
没有署名  只是写着"请妥善使用"
There was no name. It just said, "Use it well. "
《著名的食火者》
Famous Fire-Eaters.
《十五世纪的恶魔》
Fifteenth-Century Fiends.
勒梅  尼古拉斯·勒梅  你在哪里
Flamel. Nicholas Flamel. Where are you?
谁
Who's there?
我知道你在里面  躲不了的
I know you're in there. You can't hide.
是谁  快点现形
Who is it? Show yourself.
西弗勒斯  我...
Severus, I...
你不希望我和你对着干吧  奇洛
You don't want me as your enemy, Quirrell.
我不清楚你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
恰恰相反  你很清楚
You know perfectly well what I mean.
我们有空再聊
We'll have another little chat soon.
好好聊聊你究竟在替谁做事
When you've had time to decide where your loyalties lie.
教授们  我在禁书区发现了这个
Professors. I found this in the restricted section.
还烫手呢
It's still hot.
显然有学生溜出寝室了
That means there's a student out of bed.
「反过来即」：“显之非容  示之乃欲”
"I show not your face  but your heart desire"
Erised stra ehru oyt ube cafru oyt on wohsi
妈妈
Mum?
爸爸
Dad?
罗恩  你得看看这个
Ron, you've really gotta see this!
罗恩  一定得看看
Ron, you've gotta see this!
罗恩  快点  起床
Ron, Ron, come on, get out of bed!
-怎么了  -有件东西你一定得看看
- Why? - There's something you've got to see! Come on.
快  快点  看  这是我父母
Come on! Come! Come look, it's my parents!
我只看到我们俩
I only see us.
对准角度再看  站这里
Look in properly. Go on, stand there.
这儿 看到了没
There. You see them, don't you?
这是我 成了学生会主席
That's me! Only I'm head boy.
而且赢了魁地奇杯
And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup.
我的天呐  我还是魁地奇队长
And bloody hell! I'm Quidditch captain too!
看上去帅呆了
I look good.
哈利  你觉得镜子显示的是未来么
Harry, do you think this mirror shows the future?
怎么可能  我父母都已经过世了
How can it? Both my parents are dead.
喜欢你的礼物吗  罗恩
Do you like yours, Ron?
-罗恩  -我待会儿再跟你聊
- Ron? - I'll be right back.
玩象棋吗
Wanna play chess?
不
No.
去看海格吗
Wanna go and visit Hagrid?
不去
No.
哈利  我知道你在想什么
Harry, I know what you're thinking,
但是别这样
but don't.
镜子里的事情是虚幻的
There's something not right about that mirror.
又来了吗  哈利
Back again, Harry?
你和以前那些人一样
I see that you, like so many before you
在厄里斯魔镜中找到了乐趣
have discovered the delights of the Mirror of Erised.
我想现在你应该知道它的作用
I trust by now you realize what it does.
给你点提示
Let me give you a clue.
只有世上最快乐的人
The happiest man on earth
才会在镜子中会看到
would look in the mirror and see only himself
现实中的自己
exactly as he is.
那么  这是一面显示我们欲求的镜子
So then, it shows us what we want. Whatever we want.
是  也不是
Yes. And no.
它反映的其实是
It shows us nothing more or less
我们内心最最深切的渴望
than the deepest and most desperate desires of our hearts.
对于你  哈利  你从没见过家人
Now you, Harry, who have never known your family.
所以看到了他们在你身边
You see them standing beside you.
但记住  哈利
But remember this, Harry.
这块镜子不会给我们知识
This mirror gives us neither knowledge
和真相
or truth.
人们只会在它前面虚度光阴  甚至发疯
Men have wasted away in front of it. Even gone mad.
所以我明天要把它挪个地方
That is why tomorrow it will be moved to a new home.
而且我告诉你
And I must ask you
不要想着找它了
not to go looking for it again.
人不能活在梦里
It does not do to dwell on dreams
而忘记生活
and forget to live.
你好  海德薇
Hi, Hedwig.
看看你  还玩牌  真悲哀
Look at you, playing with your cards. Pathetic!
马上考试了
We've got final exams soon.
我都复习好了  随便问
I'm ready. Ask me any question.
那么遗忘药水的配方是什么
All right. What are the ingredients in a Forgetfulness Potion?
忘了
I forgot.
要是考到这个题你怎么办
What do you plan to do if it's in the exam?
-抄你啊  -不行
- Copy off you. - No, you won't.
而且  考试用的笔
Besides, we're to be given
都施了防作弊魔咒
special quills with an Anti-Cheating Spell.
这简直就是侮辱
That's insulting!
完全不信任我们
It's as if they don't trust us!
又是张邓布利多
Dumbledore again!
-锁腿咒  -马尔福干的
- Leg-Locker Curse? - Malfoy.
你得在大家面前挺住  纳威
You have got to start standing up to people. Neville
说得轻巧  我都站不牢
How? I can barely stand at all!
我来给你解咒
I'll do the counfftercurse!
不  不  还是这样好了
No, that's all I need!
我可不想把腿给烧了
You to set my kneecaps on fire!
不许嘲笑我    隆巴顿
I don't appreciate the insinuation, Longbottom.
难道大家没有发现
Besides, if anyone cared to notice
我烧掉的眉毛已经长齐了
my eyebrows have completely grown back!
我找到了
I found him!
"邓布利多因于1945年
"Dumbledore is particularly famous for
击败了黑法师格林德沃而闻名于天下"
his defeat of the dark wizard Grindelwald in 1945."
-继续  -"他发现了龙血的十二种用途
- Go on! - "For his discovery of the twelve uses of dragon blood...
阿布思·邓布利多
并与尼古拉斯·勒梅搭档  在炼金术上造诣颇深"
and his welcomed alchemy with his partner Nicholas Flamel"!
我就觉得这名字耳熟
I knew the name sounded familiar.
那天在火车上看到过
I read it on the train that day.
跟我来
Follow me!
等等  你们要去哪里
Hey! Wait! Where are you going?
说好的解咒呢
What about the countercurse?
我让你们找错了地方
I had you looking in the wrong section.
我怎么会那么笨呢
How could I be so stupid?
几周前我借了这本书解解闷
I checked this out weeks ago for a bit of light reading.
这能解闷吗
This is light?
没错  就是这个
Of course! Here it is!
尼古拉斯·勒梅是
Nicholas Flamel is the
唯一已知的魔法石制作者
only known maker of the Philosopher's Stone.
什么东西
The what?
难道你们俩从来不看书吗
Honestly, don't you two read?
魔法石
"The Philosopher's Stone
是一种具有超凡魔力的传奇物品
is a legendary substance with astonishing powers.
它可以点石成金
It'll transform any metal into pure gold,
还能制作长生不老药
and produces the Elixir of Life
让人永生
which will make the drinker immortal. "
-长生不老  -就是说你死不了
- Immortal? - It means you'll never die.
我知道是什么意思
I know what it means!
"现存的唯一魔法石
"The only Stone currently in existence
归尼古拉斯·勒梅先生所有
belongs to Mr. Nicholas Flamel,
这位著名的炼金术士
the noted alchemist who last year
去年度过了他的第665个生日"
celebrated his 665th birthday."
路威在三楼守护的就是这东西
That's what Fluffy's guarding on the third floor.
那活板门里面就是这个  魔法石
That's what's under the trap door. The Philosopher's Stone.
-海格  -你好
- Hagrid. - Oh, hello.
抱歉  无意冒犯
Sorry, don't wish to be rude,
但是今天我不能陪你们玩了
but I'm in no fit state to entertain today.
我们知道魔法石的事了
We know about the Philosopher's Stone.
我们认为斯内普想偷它
We think Snape's trying to steal it.
斯内普  你们不会还在怀疑他吧
Snape? Come on, are you still on about him, aren't you?
海格  我们知道他想得到魔法石
Hagrid, we know he's after the stone,
只是不知道什么目
we just don't know why.
斯内普是保护魔法石的老师之一
Snape is one of the teachers protecting the Stone.
他不会去偷它的
He's not about to steal it.
什么
What?
没错  你们快走吧  我今天有点忙
You heard. Alright, come on now, I'm a bit preoccupied today.
等等  "老师之一"
Wait a minute. "One of the teachers"?
这就对了
Of course!
还有其他东西在保护着魔法石  对吧
There are other things defending the Stone, aren't there?
-咒语和魔法  -没错
- Spells, enchantments. - That's right.
要我说简直是浪费时间
Waste of bloody time, if you ask me.
没有人能过得了路威这一关
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy.
谁都不知道方法  除了我和邓布利多
Ain't a soul knows how, except for me and Dumbledore.
我不该告诉你们的  我不该多嘴的
I shouldn't have told you that. I should not have told you that.
海格  那到底是什么
Hagrid, what exactly is that?
那个吗  是个  是个
That? It's a...it's um...
我知道那是什么
I know what that is!
但是海格  你是怎么弄到的
But, Hagrid, how did you get one?
我从酒吧里的一个陌生人那里赢来的
I won it. Off a stranger I met down at the pub.
说实话  那人好像巴不得送走它
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it, as a matter of fact.
那是
Is that...a dragon?
那可不是普通的龙
That's not just a dragon.
那是一条挪威脊背龙
That's a Norwegian Ridgeback.
我哥哥查理就在罗马尼亚研究它们
My brother Charlie works with these in Romania.
不觉得他很漂亮吗  上帝保佑他
Isn't he beautiful? Oh, bless him.
快看  找妈妈来了
Look, he knows his mummy.
你好  诺伯
Hello, Norbert.
诺伯
Norbert?
对啊  他总得有个名字吧
Yeah, well, he's gotta have a name, don't he?
对吧  诺伯
Don't you, Norbert?
当然了  他还是有点缺乏教养
He'll have to be trained up a bit, of course.
那是谁
Who's that?
马尔福
Malfoy.
不好了
Oh, dear.
海格一直想养一条龙
Hagrid always wanted a dragon.
第一次见到我的时候就跟我说过
Told me so the first time I ever met him.
这太疯狂了
It's crazy.
更糟的是  马尔福知道了
And worse, Malfoy knows.
-我不明白  是坏事吗  -是的
- I don't understand. Is that bad? - It's bad.
晚安
Good evening.
无论如何  我重复  无论如何
Nothing, I repeat, nothing...
学生都不能半夜里在学校里闲逛
gives a student the right to walk about the school at night.
因此  作为对你们的惩罚
Therefore, as punishment for your actions,
扣掉50分
50 points will be taken.
-50分  -每个人
-50?! - Each.
为了确保这种事不再发生
And to ensure it doesn't happen again,
你们四个都要留堂
all four of you will receive detention.
抱歉  教授  也许我听错了
Excuse me, professor, perhaps I heard you wrong.
你刚说我们四个
I thought you said the four of us.
不  我就是那么说的  马尔福先生
No, you heard me correctly, Mr Malfoy.
尽管你的出发点是好的
You see, honorable as your intentions were,
但是你也半夜跑出来了
but you too were out of bed after hours.
你要跟你的同学们一起受罚
You will join your classmates in detention.
以前的惩罚方式废除了  真可惜
A pity they let the old punishments die.
以前被罚留堂的人
There was a time detention would found you
都要倒挂在地牢里
hanging by your thumbs in the dungeons.
我真怀念那惨叫声
God, I miss the screaming.
今晚你们和海格一起留堂
You'll be serving detention with Hagrid tonight.
他要到禁林里办点事情
He's got a little job to do inside the Dark Forest.
调皮虫们来了  海格
A sorry lot, this, Hagrid.
天啊  伙计
Oh, good God, man.
你还在对那条龙念念不忘吗
You're not still on about that bloody dragon, are you?
诺伯走了
Norbert's gone.
邓布利多把他送到罗马尼亚的栖息地了
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania to live in a colony.
那是好事  不是吗
Well, that's good, isn't it?
他能和同类在一起了
He'll be with his own kind.
万一他不喜欢罗马尼亚呢
Yeah, but what if he don't like Romania?
如果其他的龙欺负他怎么办
What if the other dragons are mean to him?
他毕竟才那么小
He's only a baby after all.
得了吧  振作起来
Oh for God's sake, pulI yourself together, man.
你要进林子里去的
You're going into the Forest after all.
头脑最好保持清醒
Got to have your wits about you.
禁林  我以为你在开玩笑
The Forest? I thought that was a joke.
我们不能进去
We can't go in there.
学生不准进去的
Students aren't allowed.
而且里面有
And there are...
狼人
werewolves.
那林子里可不止有狼人
Oh, there's more than werewolves in those trees, eh.
这点可以肯定
You can be sure of that.
晚安
Nighty-night.
好了  我们走吧
Right. Let's go.
海格  那是什么
Hagrid, what is that?
我们来的目的  看到了吗
What we're here for. See that?
那是独角兽的血
That's unicorn blood, that is.
几星期前我发现有一头死掉了
I found one dead a few weeks ago.
这一头伤得很重
Now, this one's been hurt bad by something.
我们的任务
So, it's our job
就是找到那可怜的家伙
to go and find the poor beast.
罗恩  赫敏  你们跟着我
Ron, Hermione, you come with me.
好的
Ok.
哈利  你跟马尔福一起
Harry, you'll go with Malfoy.
好吧  那我要牙牙
Okay. Then I get Fang.
行  要知道  他胆小的很
Fine. Just so you know, he's a bloody coward.
我回去告诉我爸  走着瞧
You wait till my father hears about this.
这是仆人干的活
This is servant's stuff.
也许我看错了  德拉科
If I didn't know better, Draco,
你是不是害怕了
I'd say you were scared.
我才不害怕  波特
I'm not scared,  Potter.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
来吧  牙牙
Come on, Fang.
说我害怕
Scared!
怎么了  牙牙
What is it, Fang?
哈利·波特  你必须离开这里
Harry Potter, you must leave.
这里很多生物都认识你
You are known to many creatures here.
这时候的禁林不安全  尤其对于你来说
The Forest is not safe at this time. Especially for you.
你赶走的那个是什么东西
But what was that thing you saved me from?
一个怪物
A monstrous creature.
屠杀独角兽是很可怕的罪行
It is a terrible crime to slay an unicorn.
喝了独角兽的血会延续你的生命
Drinking the blood of an unicorn will keep you alive
即使你已经苟延残喘
even if you are an inch from death.
但是要付出很大的代价
But at a terrible price.
杀掉这么纯洁的生物
For you have slain something so pure
从它的血液碰到你嘴唇的那一刻起
that from the moment the blood touches your lips,
你就半生半死了
you will have a half-life.
一辈子被诅咒
A cursed life.
但是谁会选择这样活着
But who would choose such a life?
你想不到吗
Can you think of no one?
你的意思是杀了这独角兽的
Do you mean to say that thing that killed the unicorn...
那个喝了它的血的
that was drinking its blood,
是伏地魔吗
that was Voldemort?
你知道此时此刻在学校里
Do you know what is hidden in the school
藏着什么东西吗  波特先生
at this very moment, Mr. Potter?
魔法石
The Philosopher's Stone.
哈利
Harry!
你好啊  费伦泽
Hello there, Firenze.
看来你见过波特了
See you've met our young Mr. Potter.
你还好吧  哈利
You all right there, Harry?
哈利·波特  我就送你到这里
Harry Potter, this is where I leave you.
你现在安全了  祝你好运
You're safe now. Good luck.
你是说  神秘人在禁林里吗
You mean, You-Know-Who is out there right now in the Forest?
他很虚弱  靠喝独角兽的血为生
But he's weak. He's living off the unicorns.
你不明白吗  我们之前错了
Don't you see? We had it wrong.
斯内普偷魔法石不是为了自己
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself.
他是为伏地魔偷的
He wants the stone for Voldemort.
有了长生不老药  伏地魔就能再次崛起
With the Elixir of Life, Voldemort will be strong again.
他会
He'll...
他会回归的
He'll come back.
但是如果他回归了
But if he comes back,
他是不是要来杀了你
you don't think he'll try to kill you, do you?
如果他有机会  也许今晚就动手了
If he'd had the chance, he might have tried tonight.
我还担心魔药课期末考呢
And to think I've been worrying about my Potions final.
等等  我们忘记了一点
Hang on a minute. We're forgetting one thing.
伏地魔唯一害怕的人是谁
Who's the one wizard Voldemort always feared?
邓布利多
Dumbledore.
只要邓布利多在这里  哈利  你就是安全的
As long as Dumbledore is around, Harry, you're safe.
只要邓布利多在这里  没有人伤得了你
As long as Dumbledore is around, you can't be touched.
我一直以为霍格沃茨的期末考很难
I'd always heard Hogwarts' end-of-year exams were frightful,
但是却觉得挺轻松的
but I found that rather enjoyable.
那是你  你还好吧  哈利
Speak for yourself. All right there, Harry?
我的伤疤  一直在灼烧
My scar. It keeps burning.
之前也发生过
It's happened before.
这次不一样了
Not like this.
也许你该去校医院看一下
Perhaps you should see the nurse.
我想这是个警告  危险要到来了
I think it's a warning. It means danger's coming.
-这就对了  -怎么了
- Of course! - What is it?
你不觉得有点奇怪吗
Don't you think it's a bit odd
海格最渴望的东西就是一条龙
that what Hagrid wants more than anything is a dragon,
结果刚好那个陌生人就有一条
and a stranger turns up who just happens to have one?
有多少人会揣着龙蛋
I mean, how many people wander around
四处溜达
with dragon eggs in their pocket?
我之前怎么就没想明白呢
Why didn't I see it before?
海格  那龙蛋是谁给你的
Hagrid, who gave you the dragon egg?
他长的什么样
What did he look like?
我不知道  一直没看到他的脸
I don't know, I never saw his face.
他戴着兜帽
He kept his hood up.
那个陌生人  你们肯定谈过话
This stanger though, you and he must have talked.
他想知道我养过哪些生物
Well, he wanted to know what sort of creatures I looked after.
我跟他说  我说  "养过路威
I told him, I said, "After Fluffy,
养一条龙简直是小意思"
a dragon's gonna be no problem."
那他对路威感兴趣吗
Then is he interested in Fluffy?
他当然对路威感兴趣
Well, of course he was interested in Fluffy.
有多少人见过三头犬
How often do you come across a three-headed dog?
哪怕你是倒卖这个的
Even if you were in the trade.
但是我跟他说  我说  我说
But I told him, I said, I said that
"对待生物的诀窍
"The trick with any beast
就是要安抚它"
is to know how to calm him."
拿路威说吧
Take Fluffy, for example.
给他来点音乐他就睡着了
Just play him a little bit of music and he falls straight to sleep.
我不该告诉你们
I shouldn't have told you that.
你们要去哪  等等
Where are you going? Wait!
我们要见邓布利多教授  马上
We have to see professor Dumbledore. Immediately!
邓布利多教授不在这里
I'm afraid professor Dumbledore is not here.
魔法部有点紧急的事情
He received an urgent owl from the Ministry of Magic
他去伦敦了
and left immediately for London.
他走了  但是这事很重要
He's gone? But this is important!
这事有关魔法石
This is about the Philosopher's Stone!
-你怎么知道  -有人想去偷了它
- How do you know...? - Someone's going to try and steal it.
我不知道你们三个是怎么知道魔法石的
I don't know how you three found out about the Stone,
但是我保证它现在很安全
but I assure you it is perfectly well protected.
你们回宿舍去吧  安静点走
Now would you go back to your dormitories? Quietly.
海格碰到的不是陌生人  对吧
That was no stranger Hagrid have met, isn't it?
是斯内普
It was Snape.
也就是说他知道怎么绕过路威了
Which means he knows how to get past Fluffy.
-而且邓布利多不在  -下午好
- And with Dumbledore gone... - Good afternoon.
这么好的天气  你们三个小格兰芬多
Now, what would three young Gryffindors such as yourselves
在室内待着干什么呢
be doing inside on a day like this?
-我们只是  -你们要小心点
- We were just... - You ought to be careful.
别人会以为你们
People will think you're...
图谋不轨
up to something.
我们该怎么办
Now what do we do?
我们穿越活板门  就今晚
We go down the trap door. Tonight.
莱福
Trevor.
莱福  走开  你怎么在这
Trevor, go! You shouldn't be here!
你们怎么在这
Neither should you.
你们又要偷偷溜出去  对吧
You're sneaking out again, aren't you?
纳威  听着  我们
Now, Neville, listen. We were...
不  我不会放你们走的
No, I won't let you!
你们又会给格兰芬多带来麻烦的
You'll get Gryffindor into trouble again.
我跟你们拼了
I'll fight you.
纳威  我很抱歉
Neville, I'm really really sorry about this.
统统石化
Petrificus Totalus.
你有时候挺吓人的  你知道吗
You're a little scary sometimes, you know that?
很棒  但是也挺吓人
Brilliant, but scary.
我们走吧
Let's go.
-对不起  -这是为了你好
- Sorry. - It's for your own good, you know.
你踩到我的脚了
You stood on my foot!
对不起
Sorry.
阿拉霍洞开
Alohomora.
等等  他在
Wait a minute. He's...
打呼噜
snoring.
斯内普已经来了
Snape's already been here.
他对这竖琴施了咒语
He's put a spell on the harp.
它的口臭真重
It's got horrible breath.
-我们得把它的爪子挪开  -什么
- We have to move its paw. - What?
来吧
Come on!
好了  推一把
Okay. Push.
我先进去  等我给你们信号再下去
I'll go first. Don't follow until I give you a sign.
如果遇到了麻烦  你们就赶紧离开
If something bad happens, get yourselves out.
你们觉不觉得有点安静
Does it seem a bit quiet to you?
竖琴
The harp.
它停止弹奏了
It's stopped playing.
快跳
Jump!
幸好有这种植物在
Lucky this plant thing's here, really.
别动  你们俩  这是魔鬼之网
Stop moving, both of you. This is Devil's Snare.
你们必须要放松  不然的话
You have to relax. If you don't,
你会死得更快
it will only kill you faster.
死得更快  这叫我怎么放松
Kill us faster? Oh, now I can relax!
赫敏
Hermione!
-我们该怎么办  -放松
- Now what are we gonna do? - Just relax!
赫敏  你在哪里
Hermione, where are you?
按我说的做  相信我
Do what I say! Trust me.
-你没事吧  -没事  我还好
- Are you okay? - Yeah, I'm fine.
-他还是没放松  是吧  -显然是
- He's not relaxing, is he? - Apparently not.
-我们得想想办法  -什么办法
- We've gotta do something. - What?
草药课上好像读到过
I remember reading something in Herbology.
魔鬼网  魔鬼网  魔网致命
Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare. It's deadly fun
却怕太阳  没错  它怕阳光
but will sulk in the sun! That's it! Devil's Snare hates sunlight.
明亮如昼
Lumus Solem.
-罗恩  你还好吧  -还好
- Ron, you okay? - Yeah.
幸好没有慌张
Lucky we didn't panic.
幸好赫敏草药课听讲了
Lucky Hermione pays attention in Herbology.
什么声音
What is that?
不知道  像是翅膀的声音
I don't know. Sounds like wings.
奇怪  我从来没见过这种鸟
Curious. I've never seen birds like these.
那不是鸟  是钥匙
They're not birds. They're keys.
肯定有一把是开那扇门的
And I'll bet one of them fits that door.
-我们要怎么办  -我不知道
- What's this all about? - I don't know.
奇怪
Strange.
阿拉霍洞开
Alohomora!
试试总没错吧
Well, it was worth a try.
怎么办  有上千把钥匙呢
What will we do? There must be a thousand keys there.
我们要找一把古色古香的大钥匙
We want a big, old-fashioned one.
像把手一样  可能生锈了
Probably rusty like the handle.
我看到了  翅膀受伤的那把
I see it! The one with the broken wing.
怎么了  哈利
What's wrong, Harry?
这太简单了
It's too simple.
加油  哈利
Go on, Harry!
如果斯内普都能骑着旧扫帚抓住它
If Snape could catch it on that old broomstick,
那你也能
you can.
你可是一个世纪以来最年轻的找球手
You're the youngest Seeker in a century.
看来没那么简单
This complicates things a bit.
接住钥匙
Catch the key!
快点
Hurry up!
我不喜欢这里  一点也不喜欢
I don't like this. I don't like this at all.
我们在哪  墓地吗
Where are we? A graveyard.
这不是墓地
This is no graveyard.
这是个棋盘
It's a chessboard.
门在那边
There's the door.
现在我们怎么办
Now what do we do?
这还不明显吗
It's obvious, isn't it?
我们得下棋才能走到屋子的那边
We've got to play our way across the room.
[就是相]
好吧  哈利  你去那个主教的位置
Alright, Harry, you take the empty bishop's square.
赫敏  你当皇后边上的车
Hermione, you'll be the queen-side castle.
[也就是马]
至于我  我要做个骑士
As for me, I'll be a knight.
然后呢
What happens now?
白棋先走
Well, white moves first.
然后
And then
看我们的
we play.
罗恩  我们不会是要
Ron, you don't suppose this is going to be like
下真正的巫师棋吧  是吗
real wizard's chess, do you?
你  走到D5
You there, d5.
是的  赫敏
Yes, Hermione.
这和巫师棋一模一样
I think this is gonna be exactly like wizard's chess.
车到E4
Castle to e4!
卒到c3
Pawn to c3!
-等等  -没错  哈利
- Wait a minute. - You understand right, Harry.
我走完下一步  皇后会吃掉我
Once I make my move, the queen will take me.
你就可以把国王将死了
Then you're free to check the king.
-不  罗恩  不  -什么意思
- No. Ron, no! - What is it?
他要牺牲自己
He's going to sacrifice himself.
不行  一定还有别的办法
No, you can't, there must be another way!
你到底想不想阻止斯内普偷魔法石
Do you wanna stop Snape from getting that Stone or not?
哈利  你一定要继续下去  我知道
Harry, it's you that has to go on. I know it.
不是我  也不是赫敏  是你
Not me. Not Hermione. You.
马去H3
Knight to h3.
将军
Check.
罗恩
Ron!
不  别动
No, don't move!
别忘了  棋局还没结束
Don't forget, we're still playing.
将军
Checkmate.
照看好罗恩  然后去猫头鹰棚屋
Take care of Ron. Then go to the owlery.
给邓布利多送信  罗恩说得对
Send a message to Dumbledore. Ron's right.
我得继续
I have to go on.
你会没事的  哈利
You'll be okay, Harry.
你是个了不起的巫师  真的
You're a great wizard. You really are.
不如你出色
Not as good as you.
我  不过是死读书  再耍点小聪明
Me? Books and cleverness.
还有更重要的东西
There are more important things.
那就是友谊和勇气
Friendship and bravery.
哈利  你要小心
And, Harry, just be careful.
是你?
You?
不  不可能  斯内普  是他...
No, it can't be. Snape, he was the...
是啊  他确实像个坏人  不是吗
Yes, he does seem the type, doesn't he?
有他在  谁还会怀疑
Next to him, who would suspect
可怜的  结结巴巴的奇洛教授
poor, stuttering Professor Quirrell?
但是那天  魁地奇比赛上
But that day, during the Quidditch match,
斯内普想杀了我
Snape tried to kill me.
不  亲爱的  是我要杀你
No, dear boy. I tried to kill you!
相信我  要不是斯内普的斗篷着火了
And trust me, if Snape's cloak hadn't caught fire
把我撞翻了
and broken my eye contact
我本可以成功的
I would have succeeded.
斯内普再念反咒也没用
Even with Snape muttering his little countercurse.
斯内普是在救我吗
Snape was trying to save me?
我从一开始就知道你对我是个威胁
I knew you were a danger to me right from the off,
尤其是万圣节后
especially after Halloween.
是你把巨怪放进来的
Then you let the troll in!
真聪明  波特  是的
Very good, Potter, yes.
倒霉的是  斯内普起了疑心
Snape, unfortunately, wasn't fooled.
人们都跑向地牢时
While everyone was running about the dongeon,
他直接赶到四楼阻拦我
he went to the third floor to head me off.
当然  他再也不相信我了
He, of course, never trusted me again.
他很少让我单独一人  但是他不知道
He rarely left me alone. But he doesn't understand.
我从来都不是一个人  不是
I'm never alone. Never.
这面镜子是怎么回事
Now, what does this mirror do?
我看到了我的渴望
I see what I desire.
我看到我拿着魔法石
I see myself holding the Stone.
但我是怎么得到的呢
But how do I get it?
利用那个男孩
Use the boy.
过来  波特  快点
Come here, Potter! Now!
告诉我  你看到了什么
Tell me, what do you see?
怎么样  你看到了什么
What is it? What do you see?
我正在跟邓布利多握手
I'm shaking hands with Dumbledore.
我赢得了学院杯
I've won the house cup.
他在说谎
He lies.
说实话  你看到了什么
Tell the truth! What do you see?
让我跟他说
Let me speak to him.
主人  你的体力还不够
Master, you are not strong enough.
这点力气还是有的
I have strength enough for this.
哈利·波特
Harry Potter
我们又见面了
we meet again.
伏地魔
Voldemort.
是啊  你看我变成什么样子了
Yes. You see what I've become?
看我怎样苟延残喘
See what I must do to survive?
活在别人的身体里  当个寄生虫
Live off another. A mere parasite.
独角兽的血给了我些体力
Unicorn blood can sustain me
却不能给我躯体
but it cannot give me a body of my own.
但是有一样东西可以
But there is something that can.
那东西  正好就在你的口袋里
Something that, conveniently enough, lies in your pocket.
拦住他
Stop him!
别犯傻了
Don't be a fool.
何苦自寻死路
Why suffer an horrific death
不如共享永生
when you can join me and live?
休想
Never!
勇气可嘉  你父母也是如此
Bravery. Your parents had it too.
告诉我  哈利
Tell me, Harry
你想不想再见到你的父母
would you like to see your mother and father again?
我们联手
Together
可以让他们起死回生
we can bring them back.
我只要一点点回报
All I ask is for something in return.
没错  哈利
That's it, Harry.
世上本无善恶
There is no good and evil.
只有权力
There is only power
和无力追逐权力的人
and those too weak to seek it.
我们联手  可以成就大事
Together, we'll do extraordinary things.
把魔法石给我
Just give me the Stone!
你撒谎
You liar!
杀了他
Kill him!
这是什么魔法
What is this magic?
蠢货  快去抢魔法石
Fool, get the Stone!
（早日康复）
下午好  哈利
Good afternoon, Harry.
-崇拜者的礼物?  -崇拜者?
- Tokens from your admirers? - Admirers?
你和奇洛教授
What happened in the dungeons
在地下室里的故事  是个秘密
between you and Professor Quirrell is a complete secret.
秘密总是不胫而走  全校都知道了
So, naturally, the whole school knows.
看来你的朋友罗恩
I see that your friend Ronald has saved you
帮你打开了巧克力蛙
the trouble of opening your Chocolate Frogs.
罗恩来过吗  他还好吗  赫敏呢
Ron was here? Is he all right? What about Hermione?
很好  他们都很好
Fine. They're both just fine.
-魔法石呢  -放松  亲爱的
- What happened to the Stone? - Relax, dear boy.
魔法石已经被毁掉了
The Stone has been destroyed.
我和朋友尼可谈了谈
My friend Nicholas and I have had a little chat
一致认为这样最好
and agreed it was best all around.
但那样的话  勒梅会死的  不是吗
But then, Flamel, he'll die, won't he?
他有足够的长生不老药来料理后事
He has enough Elixir to set his affairs in order.
但是  他会死
But yes, he will die.
我是怎么拿到魔法石的  先生
How is it I got the Stone, sir?
我一看那面镜子...
One minute I was staring in the mirror and...
你看  必须是
You see, only a person
想要找到魔法石  找到它
who wanted to find the Stone, find it
但不利用它的人  才能得到它
but not use it, would be able to get it.
这是我的妙计之一
That is one of my more brilliant ideas.
别跟别人说  我的妙计厉害吧
And between you and me, that is saying something.
是不是说  魔法石被毁掉了
Does that mean, with the Stone gone,
伏地魔就永远消失了
that Voldemort can never come back?
恐怕
I'm afraid
他还会想办法卷土重来
there are ways in which he can return.
哈利  你知道为什么
Harry, do you know why
奇洛教授不能让你碰他吗
Professor Quirrell couldn't bear to have you touch him?
因为你的母亲  她为你牺牲了自己
It was because of your mother. She sacrificed herself for you.
那种牺牲留下了印记
And that kind of act leaves a mark.
不  是看不见的印记
No, this kind of mark cannot be seen.
-在你的身体里  -那是什么
- It lives in your very skin. - What is it?
爱  哈利  是爱
Love, Harry. Love.
比比多味豆
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans.
我年轻时真倒霉
I was most unfortunate in my youth
吃到了颗呕吐味的
to come across a vomit-flavored one.
从那以后  我就不喜欢豆子了
And since then, I'm afraid I've lost my liking for them.
不过我想  来一颗太妃糖味的
But I think I could be safe
总没问题
with a nice toffee.
倒霉
Alas!
耳屎味
Earwax.
-还好吧  罗恩  -还好  你呢
- All right there, Ron? - All right. You?
很好  赫敏呢
All right. Hermione?
再好不过了
Never better.
（斯莱特林学院）
又一年过去了
Another year gone.
没记错的话  现在要颁发学院杯
And now, as I understand it, the house cup needs awarding.
得分情况为
And the points stand thus:
第四名  格兰芬多  312分
In fourth place, Gryffindor with 312 points.
第三名  赫奇帕奇  352分
Third place, Hufflepuff with 352 points.
第二名
In second place
拉文克劳  426分
Ravenclaw with 426 points.
第一名的是
And in first place
472分的斯莱特林学院
with 472 points, Slytherin house.
干得好  伙计
Nice one, mate.
是啊  表现很好  斯莱特林  很好
Yes, well done, Slytherin. Well done.
然而  最近发生的几件事也要计算在内
However, recent events must be taken into account.
我最后还要奖励一些分数
And I have a few last-minute points to award.
赫敏·格兰杰小姐
To Miss Hermione Granger,
当大家身处险境时
for the cool use of intellect
你冷静思考
while others were in grave peril
奖励50分
50 points.
做得好
Good job.
第二项  给罗恩·韦斯莱先生
Second, to Mr. Ronald Weasley,
因为你赢下了霍格沃茨
for the best-played game of chess
许多年来最精彩的一盘棋
that Hogwarts has seen these many years,
奖励50分
50 points.
第三项
And third
哈利·波特先生
to Mr. Harry Potter
为你无畏的胆量和过人的勇气
for pure nerve and outstanding courage
我要奖励给格兰芬多学院60分
I award Gryffindor house 60 points.
我们和斯莱特林打平了
We're tied with Slytherin!
最后还有  对付敌人
Finally, it takes a great deal of bravery
我们需要很大的勇气
to stand up to your enemies
但在朋友面前坚定立场
but a great deal more
需要更大的勇气
to stand up to your friends.
我要奖励10分
I award 10 points
给纳威·隆巴顿先生
to Neville Longbottom.
如果我没算错的话
Assuming that my calculations are correct
我觉得这里的装饰需要改变一下
I believe that a change of decoration is in order.
格兰芬多赢得了学院杯
Gryffindor wins the house cup.
我们赢了,我们拿到了冠军
We won.We won
快走  快点  该迟到了
Come on, now. Hurry up, you'll be late.
火车就要开了  快走  快点
Train's leaving. Go on. Come on, hurry up.
-走吧  哈利  -等一下
- Come on, Harry. - One minute.
还以为你不告别就要走了呢
Thought you were leaving without saying goodbye, did you?
这个给你
This is for you.
谢谢  海格
Thanks, Hagrid.
走吧  走吧  记着  哈利
Go on. On with you. On with you now. Oh, listen, Harry.
要是你那个蠢货表哥达力欺负你
If that dolt of a cousin of yours, Dudley, gives you any grief
你就威胁他
you could always threaten him
给他变一副猪耳朵  配他的尾巴
with a nice pair of ears to go with that tail of his.
但是海格  我们离开霍格沃茨
But Hagrid, we're not allowed to do magic
是不能施魔法的  你知道的
away from Hogwarts. You know that.
我知道  但是你的表哥不知道  对吧
I do. But your cousin don't, do he? Right?
回家的感觉有点奇怪  不是吗
Feels strange to be going home, doesn't it?
我不是回家
I'm not going home.
不算是
Not really.